<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&amp;#128045; the tamouse pages</title>
    <description>the rumblings and ramblings of a well-traveled tech-mouse</description>
    <link>https://blog.tamouse.org/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.tamouse.org/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 23:06:06 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 23:06:06 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.5.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Quote: Chekhov, No Cure</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Anton Chekhov, in &lt;em&gt;The Cherry Orchard&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If many remedies are prescribed for an illness,
you may be certain that the illness has no cure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;
(Found at
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brainpickings.org/2017/09/27/having-it-out-with-melancholy-jane-kenyon-amanda-palmer/&quot;&gt;brainpickings.com&lt;/a&gt;
with an exceptional reading of Jane Kenyon’s poem &lt;em&gt;Having It Out With
Meloncholy&lt;/em&gt;, read by Amanda Palmer.)
&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 23:44:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://blog.tamouse.org/blog/quotes/2017/12/27/quote-chekhov-no-cure.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.tamouse.org/blog/quotes/2017/12/27/quote-chekhov-no-cure.html</guid>
        
        <category>chekhov</category>
        
        
        <category>quotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Winter: A Poem (short)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A (very) short ode to winter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Shit, it’s cold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/tt.imageshare/blog/poems/winter-poem-shit-its-cold.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A Winter Poem: Shit it's cold. The End. (Text over an image of a house in the midst of winter at night with the moon overhead and light coming from the windows)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– image unattributed, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/mayaishappy/photos/a.744611972266690.1073741830.744582278936326/1643098582418020/&quot;&gt;found
on facebook&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://tineye.com/search/a63f42103e5676c5888181781a4549c40350bf8e/?sort=crawl_date&amp;amp;order=asc&quot;&gt;Tineye&lt;/a&gt;
turned &lt;a href=&quot;https://c2.staticflickr.com/8/7561/16331979841_e356fce1e4_b.jpg&quot;&gt;this
image&lt;/a&gt; up by flickr user &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/people/toalafoto/&quot;&gt;taolfoto&lt;/a&gt; as the
oldest match.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 21:32:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://blog.tamouse.org/blog/poetry/2017/12/27/winter-a-poem-short.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.tamouse.org/blog/poetry/2017/12/27/winter-a-poem-short.html</guid>
        
        <category>poems</category>
        
        <category>poetry</category>
        
        <category>short</category>
        
        <category>funny</category>
        
        
        <category>poetry</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>BBC: Indonesia's Orang Rima Tribe Forced to Renounce Faith</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Reporting from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com&quot;&gt;BBC&lt;/a&gt;, this story is getting
banned on Facebook for “Violating Community Standards”. It’s another
story of colonialism and oppression of a native people in the
pursuit of profits in palm oil. Keep it alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;view-story-on-the-bbc-site&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-41981430&quot;&gt;View story on the BBC site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;indonesias-orang-rimba-forced-to-renounce-their-faith&quot;&gt;Indonesia’s Orang Rimba: Forced to renounce their faith&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By Rebecca Henschke BBC Indonesian Editor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;17 November 2017&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;figure-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/tt.imageshare/blog/politics/2017-12-15-bbc-indonesias-orang-rima-tribe-forced-to-renounce-faith/video-cover.jpg&quot; class=&quot;figure-img-image&quot; alt=&quot;Watch the video on the
BBC site&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;figure-img-caption&quot;&gt;Watch the video on the
BBC site&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-41981430&quot;&gt;Watch the Video on the BBC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sumatran rainforests of Indonesia are home to the Orang Rimba - the
people of the jungle. Their faith and nomadic way of life are not
recognised by the state and, as their forests are destroyed to make way
for palm oil plantations, many are being forced to convert to Islam to
survive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a wooden hut on stilts, a group of children dressed in white sit on
the floor. They sing “I will protect Islam till I die” and shout “There
is no god but Allah”, in unison
.
Three months ago, the 58 families that make up the Celitai tribe of
Orang Rimba converted to Islam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They were picked up and bussed into Jambi, the nearest city, and given
clothes and prayer mats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;figure-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/tt.imageshare/blog/politics/2017-12-15-bbc-indonesias-orang-rima-tribe-forced-to-renounce-faith/orang-rimba-boys.jpg&quot; class=&quot;figure-img-image&quot; alt=&quot;These Orang Rimba boys converted to Islam only a
few months ago&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;figure-img-caption&quot;&gt;These Orang Rimba boys converted to Islam only a
few months ago&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Islamic Defenders Front - a vigilante group whose leader is facing
charges of inciting religious violence - helped facilitate the
conversion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ustad Reyhan, from the Islamic missionary group Hidayatullah, has
stayed to make sure the new faith is practised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“For now we are focusing on the children. It’s easier to convert them -
their mind isn’t filled with other things. With the older ones it’s
harder,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Before Islam they just believed in spirits, gods and goddesses, not
the supreme god Allah.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When someone died, they didn’t even bury the dead, they just would
leave the body in the forest. Now their life has meaning and
direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;figure-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/tt.imageshare/blog/politics/2017-12-15-bbc-indonesias-orang-rima-tribe-forced-to-renounce-faith/missionary-ustad-rayhan.jpg&quot; class=&quot;figure-img-image&quot; alt=&quot;Missionary Ustad Reyhan (right) is making sure the new religion is practised&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;figure-img-caption&quot;&gt;Missionary Ustad Reyhan (right) is making sure the new religion is practised&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“[Before] they lived in the forest. They just lived for each day, each
moment. When they died, they died. But now they have a religion, they
know there is an afterlife.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;no-choice&quot;&gt;‘No choice’&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But village leader Muhammad Yusuf - Yuguk, to use his Orang Rimba name&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;was thinking about surviving in this life when he converted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It was a very heavy and difficult decision, but we feel like we have
no choice, if we want to move forward,” he says quietly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So that our children can have the same opportunities as the outsiders,
the people of the light, we had no other choice. We had to all convert
to Islam.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;figure-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/tt.imageshare/blog/politics/2017-12-15-bbc-indonesias-orang-rima-tribe-forced-to-renounce-faith/yusuf-rimba.jpg&quot; class=&quot;figure-img-image&quot; alt=&quot;Yusuf Rimba says the decision to convert to Islam was difficult&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;figure-img-caption&quot;&gt;Yusuf Rimba says the decision to convert to Islam was difficult&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outsiders are the “people of the light”, because they live in open
areas and are often in the sun, unlike the people of the jungle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The surrounding majority Muslim population calls the Orang Rimba
“Kubu”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It means that they are very dirty, they are garbage, you can’t even
look because it is so disgusting,” explains anthropologist Butet
Manurung, who has lived with the Orang Rimba for many years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It also means primitive, stupid, bad smelling - basically pre-human.
People say their evolution is not complete.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s thought there are about 3,000 Orang Rimba living in central
Sumatra.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If you came before, you would have seen our forest. It was pristine,
with huge trees,” says Yusuf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;figure-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/tt.imageshare/blog/politics/2017-12-15-bbc-indonesias-orang-rima-tribe-forced-to-renounce-faith/palm-oil-erosion.jpg&quot; class=&quot;figure-img-image&quot; alt=&quot;The forests inhabited by the Orang Rimba have been eroded by oil palm plantations&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;figure-img-caption&quot;&gt;The forests inhabited by the Orang Rimba have been eroded by oil palm plantations&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now there are seemly endless ghostly white burnt-out sticks in one
direction, and palm oil trees in neat rows in the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The absence of any natural sounds is eerie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s all gone. It happened just in the last few years. The palm
plantations came in, and then the forest started to burn,” adds Yusuf,
referring to 2015’s devastating fires, which burnt more than 21,000
sq km of forest and peat land.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;figure-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/tt.imageshare/blog/politics/2017-12-15-bbc-indonesias-orang-rima-tribe-forced-to-renounce-faith/peat-fires.jpg&quot; class=&quot;figure-img-image&quot; alt=&quot;Peat fires are harder to put out than normal forest fires&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;figure-img-caption&quot;&gt;Peat fires are harder to put out than normal forest fires&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every year, landowners start fires to clear land with devastating
effects, but those fires were catastrophic because of a longer dry
season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;figure-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/tt.imageshare/blog/politics/2017-12-15-bbc-indonesias-orang-rima-tribe-forced-to-renounce-faith/forced-state-religion.jpg&quot; class=&quot;figure-img-image&quot; alt=&quot;Orang Rimba children
had to officially adopt one of the state-recognised religions to be
able to attend school&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;figure-img-caption&quot;&gt;Orang Rimba children
had to officially adopt one of the state-recognised religions to be
able to attend school&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Half a million people were affected by the toxic haze from the fires
and dozens died from breathing problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I was terrified. We were so scared of the flames and smoke all around
us,” Yusuf tells me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His tribe ran to the nearest village to escape and this was where the
conversion process started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;endangered-population&quot;&gt;Endangered population&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“After a while, we wanted to send our children to school, but the
teacher wanted to see their birth certificates, and for that you have
to have a state religion that the government recognises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So we had a tribal meeting, and discussed what religion we would
choose, and decided to choose Islam,” says Yusuf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indonesia - the world’s largest Muslim country - officially recognises
six religions: Islam, Protestantism, Catholicism, Hinduism, Buddhism
and Confucianism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indigenous rights bodies are fighting to get recognition for the
hundreds of other faiths practised across Indonesia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The country’s constitutional court recently ruled in their favour,
finding that it was against the constitution to force people to state a
religion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rukka Sombolinggi, head of the Indigenous Peoples Alliance of the
Archipelago, has been a key figure in this fight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We have been around before the new religions arrived, but now it’s
like they rule us, and want to clean us from this country. We have to
fight back,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She says the Orang Rimba are one of the most endangered indigenous
tribes in Indonesia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;figure-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/tt.imageshare/blog/politics/2017-12-15-bbc-indonesias-orang-rima-tribe-forced-to-renounce-faith/orang-rimba-nomadic.jpg&quot; class=&quot;figure-img-image&quot; alt=&quot;Traditionally, Orang Rimba people lived nomadically, moving from place to place in the forest&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;figure-img-caption&quot;&gt;Traditionally, Orang Rimba people lived nomadically, moving from place to place in the forest&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They reached the point of complete hopelessness and saw that embracing
one of the official religions would probably help them come out of this
very bad situation. It is a matter of survival.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;no-space-to-live&quot;&gt;‘No space to live’&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I experienced a sense of the discrimination towards Orang Rimba, when I
met a remote tribe still practising this nomadic, polytheistic way of
life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were eating with them in the jungle when a police officer and local
government officials arrived and asked what we were doing and if we had
permits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Orang Rimba guide Miyak was visibly upset, and asked why such
documents would be necessary on his own land.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We have no space to live. We are always told we are nomadic people
with no religion, no culture,” he told me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Our religion is not respected. The government is always insisting that
we convert and live in houses in one place. We can’t do that. Our way
of life is not like that.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;figure-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/tt.imageshare/blog/politics/2017-12-15-bbc-indonesias-orang-rima-tribe-forced-to-renounce-faith/repressed-culture.jpg&quot; class=&quot;figure-img-image&quot; alt=&quot;Many Orang Rimba feel their culture and religion are not respected by the wider population&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;figure-img-caption&quot;&gt;Many Orang Rimba feel their culture and religion are not respected by the wider population&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why you are making our lives so difficult?” he asked the officials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The officer, Budi Jayapura, took me aside to check my documents and
said: “We need to watch over them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They don’t understand the concept of stealing. They say the fruit grew
by itself on the tree so it can be taken, but it was planted by
someone. Maybe in their belief system it is OK, but not in our
society.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-pig-problem&quot;&gt;The pig problem&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact that they hunt and eat wild pigs also creates social tensions,
he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is a Muslim community. If they see the pig’s blood and the
leftover bits, they are disturbed,” the officer explained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is taboo, or haram, for the Orang Rimba directly contrasts with
what Muslims eat, explains Mr Manurung.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Orang Rimba will not eat domesticated animals such as chickens, cows
or sheep. They think it’s a form of betrayal. You feed the animal, and
when it gets fat you eat it. The fair thing to do is to fight. Whoever
wins can eat the loser.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This clash of cultures began in the 1980s, when [85]then-President
Suharto gave land and incentives to migrants from overcrowded Java to
move and open up the jungles of Sumatra.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then, vast areas of forests, traditionally home to the Orang
Rimba, have been handed out to palm oil, rubber and pulp and paper
companies without compensation to the indigenous tribes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;figure-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/tt.imageshare/blog/politics/2017-12-15-bbc-indonesias-orang-rima-tribe-forced-to-renounce-faith/pig-hunting.png&quot; class=&quot;figure-img-image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zulkarnai, a Ministry of Forestry official, who helped facilitate the
mass conversion of the Celitai tribe, admits that as a child, he
thought the Orang Rimba weren’t human.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“One day a ‘Kubu’ child stole fruit from one of my neighbours, and he
shot him. We went over to the body, and I realised it wasn’t a kind of
animal, it was a human, just like us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I realised that we have to help them. I feel sorry for them. They will
starve if they don’t change.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last decades, millions of hectares of rainforest have been
cleared in Indonesia, in what some studies call the world’s fastest
rate of deforestation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;polluted-land&quot;&gt;Polluted land&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New palm oil plantations have been increasing at a rate of between
300,000 and 500,000 hectares per year for the past 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last 30-odd years, more than half of Sumatra’s forests have
disappeared, replaced by monoculture palm oil plantations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sigungang’s family lives on a palm oil plantation. He tries to hunt
wild pigs when they come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But if we can’t find anything, we are forced to eat palm oil fruit. It
makes your head spin,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;figure-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/tt.imageshare/blog/politics/2017-12-15-bbc-indonesias-orang-rima-tribe-forced-to-renounce-faith/struggle-to-hunt.jpg&quot; class=&quot;figure-img-image&quot; alt=&quot;Sigungang struggles to find anything to hunt after his tribe's forest was cleared&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;figure-img-caption&quot;&gt;Sigungang struggles to find anything to hunt after his tribe's forest was cleared&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The streams in the plantation are polluted with pesticide and his
family is getting stomach problems drinking from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There is no forest for them to hunt in, the water they fished in and
drank from is polluted, and so is the air,” says social affairs
minister Khofifah Parawansa, matter-of-factly. “So we are giving them
houses, villages to live in.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government - working with plantation companies - has built a number
of housing estates for the Orang Rimba.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year, President Joko Widodo announced more new housing and some
land for them, following a meeting with tribal leaders - the first
organised by an Indonesian head of state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Minister Khofifah says faith is part of this process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“On the identity card, they have to state what religion they have.
There are those that have become Muslims, some who have become
Christians. So now they are getting to know God.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But many of the housing estates have failed and are effectively ghost
towns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;figure-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/tt.imageshare/blog/politics/2017-12-15-bbc-indonesias-orang-rima-tribe-forced-to-renounce-faith/empty-housing.jpg&quot; class=&quot;figure-img-image&quot; alt=&quot;Many of the housing estates built for the Orang Rimba now lie empty&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;figure-img-caption&quot;&gt;Many of the housing estates built for the Orang Rimba now lie empty&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without work or a way to feed their family, many Orang Rimba who lived
in them briefly went back to the traces of jungle that are left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What we want is for them to stop taking away our forest. We don’t want
houses like the outsiders,” says Ngantap, one of the elders of an Orang
Rimba tribe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I am at peace and happy in the forest, I am a person of the jungle.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;figure-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/tt.imageshare/blog/politics/2017-12-15-bbc-indonesias-orang-rima-tribe-forced-to-renounce-faith/resisters.jpg&quot; class=&quot;figure-img-image&quot; alt=&quot;Ngantap vows never to leave the forest or convert.&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;figure-img-caption&quot;&gt;Ngantap vows never to leave the forest or convert.&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ngantap wears the traditional loincloth of the Rimba people, with a bag
of cigarettes hanging from the side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unmarried women traditionally wear simple sarongs covering the breasts.
Once married, the sarong is tied around the waist leaving breasts open
for feeding babies. Many now wear clothes from the outside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Ngantap insists they are holding on to their faith.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;figure-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/tt.imageshare/blog/politics/2017-12-15-bbc-indonesias-orang-rima-tribe-forced-to-renounce-faith/culture-change.jpg&quot; class=&quot;figure-img-image&quot; alt=&quot; just a few months Yusuf's wife's (left) life has dramatically changed&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;figure-img-caption&quot;&gt; just a few months Yusuf's wife's (left) life has dramatically changed&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s wrong to say we don’t have a faith. Religion is a personal right
of every person. It’s very wrong to discredit someone’s faith.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If our belief system is lost, and the gods and goddess have no forest
home, disaster will reign.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ngantap’s wife Ngerung tell me they are connected to the trees from
birth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“After a baby is born, three trees must be planted, one for the
placenta, one for the baby, one for the name. They can never be cut
down or hurt. When we walk through our forest we remind people of
this.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;figure-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/tt.imageshare/blog/politics/2017-12-15-bbc-indonesias-orang-rima-tribe-forced-to-renounce-faith/forest-connection.jpg&quot; class=&quot;figure-img-image&quot; alt=&quot;The Orang Rimba's connection to the forest begins at birth&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;figure-img-caption&quot;&gt;The Orang Rimba's connection to the forest begins at birth&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Manurung explains: “Orang Rimba worship many gods, the tiger [being]
one of the most powerful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They have a god of bees, a god of hornbill birds, gods and goddesses
of many trees. They also worship a god of water springs. They will
never go to the toilet or put soap in the river, so you can drink it
directly.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sacrifice&quot;&gt;Sacrifice&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Miyak, my guide, converted to Islam so he can travel and fight to try
and protect his family’s forest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are trying to register the forest as their ancestral land,
following a landmark 2013 court ruling which said indigenous people
have rights over forests they have lived in for centuries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;figure-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/tt.imageshare/blog/politics/2017-12-15-bbc-indonesias-orang-rima-tribe-forced-to-renounce-faith/seeking-legal-relief.jpg&quot; class=&quot;figure-img-image&quot; alt=&quot;The Makekal Hulu Orang Rimba tribe is fighting for legal recognition for its ancestral forest&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;figure-img-caption&quot;&gt;The Makekal Hulu Orang Rimba tribe is fighting for legal recognition for its ancestral forest&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He can take part in meetings but not in religious ceremonies or
rituals. As he now uses soap to wash himself and eats chicken and cows,
he can’t enter his family home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When I got educated in the outsiders’ ways, there were many things
that I had to sacrifice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But I accept that, because I am a messenger and bridge for many people
here with the outside world and the government, about our forest and
rights.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He still fears the gods and goddesses of the old religion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s the sacred people - our women shamans - [that] I fear. They can
communicate and see the gods and goddesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The shaman can become a tiger, can become an elephant if the gods are
very angry, and attack people. I am scared of that. I worry about
breaking the rules.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Miyak’s greatest fear is that is his people’s way of life will
disappear forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fighting Forest Faiths is on [86]the BBC News Channel on Saturday 18
November at 14:30 GMT and Sunday 19 November at 16:30 GMT, and at
various times across the weekend on [87]BBC World. You can also listen
to Rebecca Henschke’s World Service documentary on the [88]BBC World
Service website now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copyright © 2017 BBC.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 22:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://blog.tamouse.org/blog/politics/2017/12/15/bbc-indonesias-orang-rima-tribe-forced-to-renounce-faith.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.tamouse.org/blog/politics/2017/12/15/bbc-indonesias-orang-rima-tribe-forced-to-renounce-faith.html</guid>
        
        <category>oppression</category>
        
        <category>colonialism</category>
        
        <category>indonesia</category>
        
        <category>orang-rimba</category>
        
        <category>politics</category>
        
        <category>culture</category>
        
        
        <category>politics</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Earth and Moon: 25 Years Ago</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;25 years ago, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://solarsystem.nasa.gov/missions/galileo&quot; title=&quot;Learn about
the Galileo project at NASA&quot;&gt;Galileo
spacecraft&lt;/a&gt; was on a trajectory towards
Jupiter, swinging past Earth and the Moon, taking this series of images.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/dGVYC4UZQs8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are real images! We hardly ever get to see this view, and images
tend to look a bit fake, or CGI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/ugordan/4200521241/in/photostream/&quot; title=&quot;See individual images on Flickr&quot;&gt;Details of Images from Gordan Ukargovik on Flickr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://apod.nasa.gov/apod/ap171204.html&quot;&gt;https://apod.nasa.gov/apod/ap171204.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 23:56:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://blog.tamouse.org/blog/apod/2017/12/03/earth-and-moon-25-years-ago.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.tamouse.org/blog/apod/2017/12/03/earth-and-moon-25-years-ago.html</guid>
        
        <category>apod</category>
        
        <category>astronomy</category>
        
        <category>galileo</category>
        
        <category>nasa</category>
        
        
        <category>apod</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I, Too. Langston Hughes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Langston Hughes, black American poet, wrote the poem “I, Too”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I, too, sing America.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;I am the darker brother. &lt;br /&gt;
They send me to eat in the kitchen &lt;br /&gt;
When company comes, &lt;br /&gt;
But I laugh, &lt;br /&gt;
And eat well, &lt;br /&gt;
And grow strong. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Tomorrow, &lt;br /&gt;
I’ll be at the table &lt;br /&gt;
When company comes. &lt;br /&gt;
Nobody’ll dare &lt;br /&gt;
Say to me, &lt;br /&gt;
“Eat in the kitchen,” &lt;br /&gt;
Then. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Besides, &lt;br /&gt;
They’ll see how beautiful I am &lt;br /&gt;
And be ashamed — &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;I, too, am America.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2017 21:02:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://blog.tamouse.org/blog/poems/2017/07/04/i-too-langston-hughes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.tamouse.org/blog/poems/2017/07/04/i-too-langston-hughes.html</guid>
        
        <category>poems</category>
        
        <category>langston-hughes</category>
        
        <category>america</category>
        
        
        <category>poems</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Danez Smith: Alternate Heaven for Black Boys</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;St. Paul poet, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.danezsmithpoet.com/&quot;&gt;Danez Smith&lt;/a&gt; wrote
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ivNWzr-Zue8&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alternate Heaven for a Black Boy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a powerful
plea to end the continuing violence perpetrated by white america.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h1 id=&quot;paradise-is-a-world-where-everything-is-a-sanctuary-and-nothing-is-a-gun&quot;&gt;Paradise is a world, where everything is a sanctuary and nothing is a gun&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//tt.imageshare.s3.amazonaws.com/blog/poems/danez-smith-alternate-heavevn-for-black-boys.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image from video of Danez Smith's performance of Alternate Heaven
for Black Boys&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a tremendously powerful piece of art. Watch it in full.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;black-lives-matter&quot;&gt;black lives matter&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-responsive embed-responsive-4by3&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe class=&quot;embed-responsive-item&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ivNWzr-Zue8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2017 16:49:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://blog.tamouse.org/blog/poems/2017/07/02/danez-smith-alternate-heaven-for-black-boys.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.tamouse.org/blog/poems/2017/07/02/danez-smith-alternate-heaven-for-black-boys.html</guid>
        
        <category>poems</category>
        
        <category>danez-smith</category>
        
        <category>blm</category>
        
        <category>black-lives-matter</category>
        
        <category>justice</category>
        
        <category>speech</category>
        
        
        <category>poems</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A picture of our times</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/tt.imageshare/blog/politics/2017-06-11-a-picture-for-our-times/comey-testifying.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Photo of Director Comey testifying before Congress, June 9, 2017&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 21:36:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://blog.tamouse.org/blog/politics/2017/06/11/a-picture-of-our-times.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.tamouse.org/blog/politics/2017/06/11/a-picture-of-our-times.html</guid>
        
        <category>comey</category>
        
        <category>testifying</category>
        
        <category>trump</category>
        
        
        <category>politics</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Carrier Bag Theory of Fiction, by Ursula K. LeGuin</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I found this some obscure place, and wanted to house it someplace I
can find it again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-carrier-bag-theory-of-fiction&quot;&gt;The Carrier Bag Theory of Fiction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;By: Ursula K. Le Guin 1986&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Source: Dancing at the Edge of the World&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transcribed: by Cody Jones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In the temperate and tropical regions where it appears that hominids evolved into human beings, the principal food of the species was vegetable. Sixty-five to eighty percent of what human beings ate in those regions in Paleolithic, Neolithic, and prehistoric times was gathered; only in the extreme Arctic was meat the staple food. The mammoth hunters spectacularly occupy the cave wall and the mind, but what we actually did to stay alive and fat was gather seeds, roots, sprouts, shoots, leaves, nuts, berries, fruits, and grains, adding bugs and mollusks and netting or snaring birds, fish, rats, rabbits, and other tuskless small fry to up the protein. And we didn’t even work hard at it–much less hard than peasants slaving in somebody else’s field after agriculture was invented, much less hard than paid workers since civilization was invented. The average prehistoric person could make a nice living in about a fifteen-hour work week.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Fifteen hours a week for subsistence leaves a lot of time for other things. So much time that maybe the restless ones who didn’t have a baby around to enliven their life, or skill in making or cooking or singing, or very interesting thoughts to think, decided to slope off and hunt mammoths. The skillful hunters then would come staggering back with a load of meat, a lot of ivory, and a story. It wasn’t the meat that made the difference. It was the story.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;It is hard to tell a really gripping tale of how I wrested a wild-oat seed from its husk, and then another, and then another, and then another, and then another, and then I scratched my gnat bites, and Ool said something funny, and we went to the creek and got a drink and watched newts for a while, and then I found another patch of oats…. No, it does not compare, it cannot compete with how I thrust my spear deep into the titanic hairy flank while Oob, impaled on one huge sweeping tusk, writhed screaming, and blood spouted everywhere in crimson torrents, and Boob was crushed to jelly when the mammoth fell on him as I shot my unerring arrow straight through eye to brain.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;That story not only has Action, it has a Hero. Heroes are powerful. Before you know it, the men and women in the wild-oat patch and their kids and the skills of the makers and the thoughts of the thoughtful and the songs of the singers are all part of it, have all been pressed into service in the tale of the Hero. But it isn’t their story. It’s his.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;When she was planning the book that ended up as Three Guineas, Virginia Woolf wrote a heading in her notebook, “Glossary”; she had thought of reinventing English according to a new plan, in order to tell a different story. One of the entries in this glossary is heroism, defined as “botulism.” And hero, in Woolf’s dictionary, is “bottle.” The hero as bottle, a stringent reevaluation. I now propose the bottle as hero.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Not just the bottle of gin or wine, but bottle in its older sense of container in general, a thing that holds something else.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;If you haven’t got something to put it in, food will escape you–even something as uncombative and unresourceful as an oat. You put as many as you can into your stomach while they are handy, that being the primary container; but what about tomorrow morning when you wake up and it’s cold and raining and wouldn’t it be good to have just a few handfuls of oats to chew on and give little Oom to make her shut up, but how do you get more than one stomachful and one handful home? So you get up and go to the damned soggy oat patch in the rain, and wouldn’t it be a good thing if you had something to put Baby Oo Oo in so that you could pick the oats with both hands? A leaf a gourd a shell a net a bag a sling a sack a bottle a pot a box a container. A holder. A recipient.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The first cultural device was probably a recipient …. Many theorizers feel that the earliest cultural inventions must have been a container to hold gathered products and some kind of sling or net carrier.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So says Elizabeth Fisher in Women’s Creation (McGraw-Hill, 1975). But no, this cannot be. Where is that wonderful, big, long, hard thing, a bone, I believe, that the Ape Man first bashed somebody with in the movie and then, grunting with ecstasy at having achieved the first proper murder, flung up into the sky, and whirling there it became a space ship thrusting its way into the cosmos to fertilize it and produce at the end of the movie a lovely fetus, a boy of course, drifting around the Milky Way without (oddly enough) any womb, any matrix at all? I don’t know. I don’t even care. I’m not telling that story. We’ve heard it, we’ve all heard all about all the sticks spears and swords, the things to bash and poke and hit with, the long, hard things, but we have not heard about the thing to put things in, the container for the thing contained. That is a new story. That is news.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And yet old. Before–once you think about it, surely long before–the weapon, a late, luxurious, superfluous tool; long before the useful knife and ax; right along with the indispensable whacker, grinder, and digger– for what’s the use of digging up a lot of potatoes if you have nothing to lug ones you can’t eat home in–with or before the tool that forces energy outward, we made the tool that brings energy home. It makes sense to me. I am an adherent of what Fisher calls the Carrier Bag Theory of human evolution.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This theory not only explains large areas of theoretical obscurity and avoids large areas of theoretical nonsense (inhabited largely by tigers, foxes, other highly territorial mammals); it also grounds me, personally, in human culture in a way I never felt grounded before. So long as culture was explained as originating from and elaborating upon the use of long, hard objects for sticking, bashing, and killing, I never thought that I had, or wanted, any particular share in it. (“What Freud mistook for her lack of civilization is woman’s lack of loyalty to civilization,” Lillian Smith observed.) The society, the civilization they were talking about, these theoreticians, was evidently theirs; they owned it, they liked it; they were human, fully human, bashing, sticking, thrusting, killing. Wanting to be human too, I sought for evidence that I was; but if that’s what it took, to make a weapon and kill with it, then evidently I was either extremely defective as a human being, or not human at all.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;That’s right, they said. What you are is a woman. Possibly not human at all, certainly defective. Now be quiet while we go on telling the Story of the Ascent of Man the Hero.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Go on, say I, wandering off towards the wild oats, with Oo Oo in the sling and little Oom carrying the basket. You just go on telling how the mammoth fell on Boob and how Cain fell on Abel and how the bomb fell on Nagasaki and how the burning jelly fell on the villagers and how the missiles will fall on the Evil Empire, and all the other steps in the Ascent of Man.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;If it is a human thing to do to put something you want, because it’s useful, edible, or beautiful, into a bag, or a basket, or a bit of rolled bark or leaf, or a net woven of your own hair, or what have you, and then take it home with you, home being another, larger kind of pouch or bag, a container for people, and then later on you take it out and eat it or share it or store it up for winter in a solider container or put it in the medicine bundle or the shrine or the museum, the holy place, the area that contains what is sacred, and then next day you probably do much the same again–if to do that is human, if that’s what it takes, then I am a human being after all. Fully, freely, gladly, for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Not, let it be said at once, an unaggressive or uncombative human being. I am an aging, angry woman laying mightily about me with my handbag, fighting hoodlums off. However I don’t, nor does anybody else, consider myself heroic for doing so. It’s just one of those damned things you have to do in order to be able to go on gathering wild oats and telling stories.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;It is the story that makes the difference. It is the story that hid my humanity from me, the story the mammoth hunters told about bashing, thrusting, raping, killing, about the Hero. The wonderful, poisonous story of Botulism. The killer story.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;It sometimes seems that that story is approaching its end. Lest there be no more telling of stories at all, some of us out here in the wild oats, amid the alien corn, think we’d better start telling another one, which maybe people can go on with when the old one’s finished. Maybe. The trouble is, we’ve all let ourselves become part of the killer story, and so we may get finished along with it. Hence it is with a certain feeling of urgency that I seek the nature, subject, words of the other story, the untold one, the life story.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;It’s unfamiliar, it doesn’t come easily, thoughtlessly to the lips as the killer story does; but still, “untold” was an exaggeration. People have been telling the life story for ages, in all sorts of words and ways. Myths of creation and transformation, trickster stories, folktales, jokes, novels…&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The novel is a fundamentally unheroic kind of story. Of course the Hero has frequently taken it over, that being his imperial nature and uncontrollable impulse, to take everything over and run it while making stern decrees and laws to control his uncontrollable impulse to kill it. So the Hero has decreed through his mouthpieces the Lawgivers, first, that the proper shape of the narrative is that of the arrow or spear, starting here and going straight there and THOK! hitting its mark (which drops dead); second, that the central concern of narrative, including the novel, is conflict; and third, that the story isn’t any good if he isn’t in it.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;I differ with all of this. I would go so far as to say that the natural, proper, fitting shape of the novel might be that of a sack, a bag. A book holds words. Words hold things. They bear meanings. A novel is a medicine bundle, holding things in a particular, powerful relation to one another and to us.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;One relationship among elements in the novel may well be that of conflict, but the reduction of narrative to conflict is absurd. (I have read a how-to-write manual that said, “A story should be seen as a battle,” and went on about strategies, attacks, victory, etc.) Conflict, competition, stress, struggle, etc., within the narrative conceived as carrier bag/belly/box/house/medicine bundle, may be seen as necessary elements of a whole which itself cannot be characterized either as conflict or as harmony, since its purpose is neither resolution nor stasis but continuing process.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Finally, it’s clear that the Hero does not look well in this bag. He needs a stage or a pedestal or a pinnacle. You put him in a bag and he looks like a rabbit, like a potato.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;That is why I like novels: instead of heroes they have people in them.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So, when I came to write science-fiction novels, I came lugging this great heavy sack of stuff, my carrier bag full of wimps and klutzes, and tiny grains of things smaller than a mustard seed, and intricately woven nets which when laboriously unknotted are seen to contain one blue pebble, an imperturbably functioning chronometer telling the time on another world, and a mouse’s skull; full of beginnings without ends, of initiations, of losses, of transformations and translations, and far more tricks than conflicts, far fewer triumphs than snares and delusions; full of space ships that get stuck, missions that fail, and people who don’t understand. I said it was hard to make a gripping tale of how we wrested the wild oats from their husks, I didn’t say it was impossible. Who ever said writing a novel was easy?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;If science fiction is the mythology of modern technology, then its myth is tragic. “Technology,” or “modern science” (using the words as they are usually used, in an unexamined shorthand standing for the “hard” sciences and high technology founded upon continuous economic growth), is a heroic undertaking, Herculean, Promethean, conceived as triumph, hence ultimately as tragedy. The fiction embodying this myth will be, and has been, triumphant (Man conquers earth, space, aliens, death, the future, etc.) and tragic (apocalypse, holocaust, then or now).&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;If, however, one avoids the linear, progressive, Time’s-(killing)-arrow mode of the Techno-Heroic, and redefines technology and science as primarily cultural carrier bag rather than weapon of domination, one pleasant side effect is that science fiction can be seen as a far less rigid, narrow field, not necessarily Promethean or apocalyptic at all, and in fact less a mythological genre than a realistic one.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;It is a strange realism, but it is a strange reality.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Science fiction properly conceived, like all serious fiction, however funny, is a way of trying to describe what is in fact going on, what people actually do and feel, how people relate to everything else in this vast sack, this belly of the universe, this womb of things to be and tomb of things that were, this unending story. In it, as in all fiction, there is room enough to keep even Man where he belongs, in his place in the scheme of things; there is time enough to gather plenty of wild oats and sow them too, and sing to little Oom, and listen to Ool’s joke, and watch newts, and still the story isn’t over. Still there are seeds to be gathered, and room in the bag of stars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 20:07:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://blog.tamouse.org/blog/philsophy/2017/06/03/carrier-bag-theory-by-ursula-k-leguin.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.tamouse.org/blog/philsophy/2017/06/03/carrier-bag-theory-by-ursula-k-leguin.html</guid>
        
        <category>leguin</category>
        
        <category>carrier</category>
        
        <category>bag</category>
        
        <category>theory</category>
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
        <category>critique</category>
        
        <category>critical-thought</category>
        
        <category>essay</category>
        
        
        <category>philsophy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>IRON Pirate Garage Buell XB9 Cafe Racer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This beauty came across my feeds a year ago, and popped back up on
facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go visit and follow the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/pg/ironpirategarage/photos/?tab=album&amp;amp;album_id=1198502130160119&quot;&gt;IRON Pirate Facebook page&lt;/a&gt; if you dare. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;figure-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://tt.imageshare.s3.amazonaws.com/blog/motorsports/Buell-XB9-Cafe-Racer-by-IRON-Pirate-Garage/buell-xb9-iron-pirate-01.jpg&quot; class=&quot;figure-img-image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;figure-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://tt.imageshare.s3.amazonaws.com/blog/motorsports/Buell-XB9-Cafe-Racer-by-IRON-Pirate-Garage/buell-xb9-iron-pirate-02.jpg&quot; class=&quot;figure-img-image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;figure-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://tt.imageshare.s3.amazonaws.com/blog/motorsports/Buell-XB9-Cafe-Racer-by-IRON-Pirate-Garage/buell-xb9-iron-pirate-03.jpg&quot; class=&quot;figure-img-image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;figure-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://tt.imageshare.s3.amazonaws.com/blog/motorsports/Buell-XB9-Cafe-Racer-by-IRON-Pirate-Garage/buell-xb9-iron-pirate-04.jpg&quot; class=&quot;figure-img-image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;figure-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://tt.imageshare.s3.amazonaws.com/blog/motorsports/Buell-XB9-Cafe-Racer-by-IRON-Pirate-Garage/buell-xb9-iron-pirate-05.jpg&quot; class=&quot;figure-img-image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 01:52:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://blog.tamouse.org/blog/motorsports/2017/05/22/iron-pirate-garage-buell-xb9-cafe-racer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.tamouse.org/blog/motorsports/2017/05/22/iron-pirate-garage-buell-xb9-cafe-racer.html</guid>
        
        <category>buell</category>
        
        <category>motorcycles</category>
        
        <category>cafe-racers</category>
        
        <category>machinery-as-art</category>
        
        
        <category>motorsports</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Amazing Legerro, a custom by Walt Siegl</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This was posted back in 2013, I think, or at least that’s when I
remember seeing it for the first time. I was astounded by the beauty
of this machine, I had it blown up on my computer desktop for
months. The Legerro is a series of project bikes by builder Walt
Siegl, based on the mighty Ducati.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;figure-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;//s3.amazonaws.com/tt.imageshare/blog/motorsports/2017-05-19-walt-sielg-legerro/walt-siegl-0.jpg&quot; class=&quot;figure-img-image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;figure-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;//s3.amazonaws.com/tt.imageshare/blog/motorsports/2017-05-19-walt-sielg-legerro/walt-siegl-5.jpg&quot; class=&quot;figure-img-image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 19:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://blog.tamouse.org/blog/motorsports/2017/05/19/walt-siegl-legerro.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.tamouse.org/blog/motorsports/2017/05/19/walt-siegl-legerro.html</guid>
        
        <category>motorcycles</category>
        
        <category>bikes</category>
        
        <category>caferacers</category>
        
        <category>sportsbikes</category>
        
        <category>siegl</category>
        
        <category>legerro</category>
        
        <category>amazing</category>
        
        
        <category>motorsports</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
<!-- touch 1 -->
