<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&amp;#128045; the tamouse pages</title>
    <description>the rumblings and ramblings of a well-traveled tech-mouse</description>
    <link>http://blog.tamouse.org/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.tamouse.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 22:55:09 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 22:55:09 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Emma Watson Quote: Feminism is not a stick to beat other women with</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Giving an interview to Reuters during pressers for the new live-action
film “Beauty and the Beast”, actor Emma Watson summed up the essense
of what is wrong with white, non-intersectional feminism:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“It just always reveals to me how many misconceptions and what a misunderstanding there is about what feminism is,” she said during an interview with Reuters. “Feminism is about giving women choice, feminism is not a stick with which to beat other women with, it’s about freedom, it’s about liberation, it’s about equality. I really don’t know what my tits have to do with it. It’s very confusing.”
– Emma Watson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 22:44:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.tamouse.org/feminism/2017/03/05/emma-watson-quote-feminism-is-not-a-stick-to-beat-other-women-with.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.tamouse.org/feminism/2017/03/05/emma-watson-quote-feminism-is-not-a-stick-to-beat-other-women-with.html</guid>
        
        <category>emma-watson</category>
        
        <category>feminism</category>
        
        <category>quote</category>
        
        
        <category>feminism</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>It is not normal... (tumblr)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Over on tumblr…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;tumblr-post&quot; data-href=&quot;https://embed.tumblr.com/embed/post/qqNvGYhq3c_RzjpEWaoRdw/123007553626&quot; data-did=&quot;1024447b735ddde2fb37e02ec89b5639b8390d72&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://transcendentalbrilliance.tumblr.com/post/123007553626/its-not-normal-for-your-boyfriend-to-ignore-you&quot;&gt;http://transcendentalbrilliance.tumblr.com/post/123007553626/its-not-normal-for-your-boyfriend-to-ignore-you&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.tumblr.com/post.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in plain text:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it’s not normal for your boyfriend to ignore you when you want to talk to him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it’s not normal for your boyfriend to shove you when he’s angry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it’s not normal for your boyfriend to call you a dumbass or a bitch when you’re in an argument.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it’s not normal for your boyfriend to threaten to leave the relationship every time you defend yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it’s not normal for your boyfriend to invalidate your feelings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it’s not normal for your boyfriend to not tell you who he’s with or where he’s going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it’s not normal for your boyfriend to keep making the same detrimental mistake over and over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it’s not normal for your boyfriend to use your insecurities against you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it’s not normal for your boyfriend to make you feel guilty for having desires and needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it’s not normal for your boyfriend to tell you that you’re stupid when you cry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it’s not normal for your boyfriend to cheat on you because he’s “just a stupid guy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it’s not normal for your boyfriend to rely on you when he doesn’t do a thing for himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it’s not normal for your boyfriend to hurt you intentionally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;please stop normalizing toxic romantic relationships. it’s not healthy
for your partner to upset you and behave recklessly as long as he
apologizes later. apologies mean nothing after he has repeatedly
disrespected you. kisses and hugs mean nothing after he has repeatedly
disrespected you. public displays of affection mean nothing after he
has repeatedly disrespected you. promises mean nothing after he has
repeatedly disrespected you. it is not okay for him to hurt you
physically or emotionally because he said he’ll change. he hasn’t. he
won’t. get out now because THIS! IS! NOT! NORMAL! other couples do not
go through this. other couples did NOT have to go through this to be
in a happy, wholesome place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;he is manipulative and selfish and he is making you weak every time
you agree to stay. even when you feel like “maybe this time, things
will be okay,” they won’t – that’s what he wants you to think so you
never slip from his grasp. you know as well as i do you’re 50 times
overdue for “this is his last chance.” this is not normal.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 20:47:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.tamouse.org/oppression/2017/03/05/it-is-not-normal-dot-dot-dot-tumblr.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.tamouse.org/oppression/2017/03/05/it-is-not-normal-dot-dot-dot-tumblr.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>oppression</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Anxiety Behaviours</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Anxiety can be very harmful and it’s not something to be overlooked.
The worst problem is that a lot of people can’t understand the effects
it can have on a person and find anxious people as being lazy,
irresponsible and passive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are not an anxious person, knowing this can help you understand
anxiety a bit better. If you are, we are sure you are going to agree
with these things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;decline-invites-although-you-may-want-to-go&quot;&gt;Decline invites although you may want to go&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are certain days that you may have planned all along and when
they come, anxiety takes up the whole space. It can become so
debilitating that you feel as if you lack the energy to go out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are aware of what is happening to you and you don’t want to become
a burden where you are supposed to go - so you just cancel everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;obsess-over-trivial-things-other-people-may-not-even-notice&quot;&gt;Obsess over trivial things other people may not even notice&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A simple word or an unintended glance from someone is enough for your
head to start processing and rewinding the situation even for days! The
truth is you obsess over everything that has happened recently or a
week ago, or any time ago, really.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may obsess over a conversation you had, or the fact that someone
hasn’t texted you yet (after a whole 12 hour period) or really just
over the fact that some stranger looked at you as if they knew you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever the case may be, many would get confused by the notion that
you even notice such things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;go-to-bed-late-wake-up-early-in-the-morning&quot;&gt;Go to bed late, wake up early in the morning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest issues for you is certainly sleeping. Of all the
processing in your head after the day, you find it hard to go to bed on
time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When early morning comes, your anxiety clock starts ticking again and
ringing several alarms to get things going - even though you are tired.
When your anxiety has switched on (by waking up), you can’t do anything
to switch it off, so you don’t go back to bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;in-every-situation-the-worst-scenario-is-your-biggest-thought&quot;&gt;In every situation, the worst scenario is your biggest thought&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of enjoying the moment as it is, you can’t help picturing and
convincing yourself that the worst scenario is inevitable. If it’s a
first date, you are convinced that something will go terribly wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you get sick, you always manage to connect the symptoms to the worst
diseases you can imagine. It’s as if your mind tricks you into
believing that nothing can go right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;you-rewind-conversations-in-your-head---over-and-over-again&quot;&gt;You rewind conversations in your head - over and over again&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter how well a conversation went with somebody, you always replay
that conversation in your head fearing that you may have said something
wrong. That’s why you try to avoid confrontation at all cost.
[INS: :INS]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This constant rewinding seems to be able to haunt you until it starts
chipping a hole from the inside. You always have to remind yourself
that it’s your anxiety talking and that there is most certainly nothing
wrong with what you have said in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;when-someone-shows-concern-about-you-you-become-even-more-worried-about-the-same-thing&quot;&gt;When someone shows concern about you, you become even more worried about the same thing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If someone notices that you are not OK and shows concern, your anxiety
grows even more. The thing is, when you hear someone asking if you are
alright, it makes you fear even more for yourself and your state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You think - if it has become noticeable, then there has to be more to
it than I thought. This makes you feel worse than you did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;you-believe-that-you-are-to-blame-if-someone-doesnt-reply-right-away&quot;&gt;You believe that you are to blame if someone doesn’t reply right away&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When communicating with people, be it your significant other, a friend
or a relative, if they don’t respond immediately, you start thinking
that you may have said or done something wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, you should stop and consider that they may be in the middle of
something that takes up their attention, or that they are just bad at
communicating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;you-are-experiencing-a-breakdown-when-the-future-comes-as-a-topic&quot;&gt;You are experiencing a breakdown when the future comes as a topic&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While most people look forward to the future and make plans for the
future, your view on the future is making you feel intimidated and
frustrated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Experiencing the present so hard makes you think how hard and daunting
the future may be. This makes you retreat and hide from the thought of
it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;you-always-compare-your-success-to-others-who-are-your-age&quot;&gt;You always compare your success to others who are your age&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although you may not want to compare yourself to others, your anxiety
makes you scour through Facebook and stay up to date with all the
successful things your peers have done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your worries are not that they have managed to succeed, but if you are
ever going to succeed in your life like they have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;you-replay-every-mistake-you-make-and-beat-yourself-up-over-it&quot;&gt;You replay every mistake you make and beat yourself up over it&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The worst scenario is making a mistake at work. The thoughts that will
consume you afterwards are tremendously difficult to handle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although you strive to perfect whatever you are doing, mistakes can
occur, which is natural. Unfortunately, your anxiety doesn’t know that.
In such cases, it becomes your worst enemy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-some-days-you-are-too-physically-and-mentally-exhausted-to-even-get-out-of-bed&quot;&gt;On some days, you are too physically and mentally exhausted to even get out of bed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anxiety burns up most of your energy, both mentally and physically.
That’s why it can happen that you cannot function properly and you just
want to remain in bed and leave yourself drown in the sheets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This paralysis comes as a result of the overwhelming experiences due
to your anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 13:13:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.tamouse.org/psychology/2017/02/20/anxiety-behaviours.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.tamouse.org/psychology/2017/02/20/anxiety-behaviours.html</guid>
        
        <category>anxiety</category>
        
        
        <category>psychology</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>tweet: largest protest in US history</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The data is in: 2017 Womens March largest protest in USA history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Via UConn prof &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/djpressman&quot;&gt;@djpressman&lt;/a&gt;, between 3.3 million to 4.2 million people marched today. Largest protests in US history &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/DA6gR2QFs6&quot;&gt;https://t.co/DA6gR2QFs6&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/O3PZ6O6Dim&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/O3PZ6O6Dim&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Ari Berman (@AriBerman) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AriBerman/status/823001984085164032&quot;&gt;January 22, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 22:54:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.tamouse.org/politics/2017/01/21/tweet-largest-protest-in-us-history.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.tamouse.org/politics/2017/01/21/tweet-largest-protest-in-us-history.html</guid>
        
        <category>womensmarch</category>
        
        
        <category>politics</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>List of Positive Things in 2016</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The intrepid Commander Chris Hadfield tweeted a list of good things
that happened in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;With celebrity death and elections taking the media by the
nose, it’s easy to forget that this year saw a great many
positives. Let’s look.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Chris Hadfield (@Cmdr_Hadfield) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Cmdr_Hadfield/status/815294057102667778&quot;&gt;December
31, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The Colombian government and FARC rebels committed to a lasting
peace, ending a war that killed or displaced over 7 million people.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Sri Lanka spent five years working to exile the world’s deadliest
disease from their borders. As of 2016, they are malaria free.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The Giant Panda, arguably the world’s second cutest panda, has
official been removed from the endangered species list.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;@astro_timpeake became the first ESA astronaut from the UK,
symbolizing a renewed British commitment to space exploration.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Tiger numbers around the world are on the rise for the first time
in 100 years, with plans to double by 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Juno, a piece of future history, successfully flew over 588 million
miles and is now sending back unprecedented data from Jupiter.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The number of veterans in the US who are homeless has halved in the
past half-decade, with a nearly 20% drop in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Malawi lowered its HIV rate by 67%, and in the past decade have
seen a shift in public health that has saved over 250,000 lives.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Air travel continue to get safer, and 2016 saw the second fewest
per capita deaths in aviation of any year on record.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;India’s dogged commitment to reforestation saw a single day event
planting more than 50 million trees, a world record.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Measles has been eradicated from the Americas. A 22 year
vaccination campaign has led to the elimination of the historic
virus.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;After a century, Einstein’s theory of gravitational waves has been
proven correct, in a ‘moon shot’ scientific achievement.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;China has announced a firm date for the end of the ivory trade, as
public opinion is becoming more staunchly environmentalist.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;A solar powered airplane flew across the Pacific Ocean for the
first time, highlighting a new era of energy possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Costa Rica’s entire electrical grid ran on renewable energy for
over half the year, and their capacity continues to grow.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Israeli and US researchers believe they are on the brink of being
able to cure radiation sickness, after successful tests this year.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The ozone layer has shown that through tackling a problem head on,
the world can stem environmental disasters, together.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;A new treatment for melanoma has seen a 40% survival rate, taking
a huge step forward towards long-term cancer survivability.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;An Ebola vaccine was developed by Canadian researchers with 100%
efficacy. Humans eradicated horror, together.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;British Columbia protected 85% of the world’s largest temperate
rainforest, in a landmark environmental agreement.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;2016 saw the designation of more than 40 new marine sanctuaries in
20 countries, covering an area larger than the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;These marine reserves include Malaysia’s 13 year struggle to
complete a million hectare park, completed this year.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;This also includes the largest marine reserve in history, created
in Antarctica via an unprecedented agreement by 24 nations.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Atmospheric acid pollution, once a gloomy reality, has been
tackled to the point of being almost back to pre-industrial
levels.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Major diseases are in decline. The US saw a 50% mortality drop in
colon cancer; lower heart disease, osteoporosis and dementia.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Uruguay successfully fought tobacco companies to create a
precedent for small countries looking to introduce health-focused
legislation.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;World hunger has reached its lowest point in 25 years, and with
poverty levels dropping worldwide, seems likely to continue.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The A.U. made strides to become more unified, launching an
all-Africa passport meant to allow for visa-free travel for all
citizens.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Fossil fuel emissions flatlined in 2016, with the Paris agreement
becoming the fastest UN treaty to become international law.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;China announced a ban on new coal mines, with renewed targets to
increase electrical capacity through renewables by 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;One third of Dutch prison cells are empty as the crime rate shrank
by more than 25% in the last eight years, continuing to drop.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;In August went to the high Arctic with some incredible young
artists. They helped open my eyes to the promise of the next
generation.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Science, economics, and environmentalism saw a reversal in the
overfishing trends of the United States this year.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;@BoyanSlat successfully tested his Ocean Cleanup prototype, and
aims to clean up to 40% of ocean-borne plastics starting this
year.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Israel now produces 55% of its freshwater, turning what is one of
the driest countries on earth into an agricultural heartland.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The Italian government made it harder to waste food, creating laws
that provided impetus to collect, share and donate excess meals.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;People pouring ice on their head amusingly provided the ALS
foundation with enough funding to isolate a genetic cause of the
disease.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Manatees, arguably the most enjoyable animal to meet when
swimming, are no longer endangered.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Grizzlies, arguable the least enjoyable animal to meet while
swimming, no longer require federal protection in US national
parks.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Global aid increased 7%, with money being designated to helping
the world’s 65 million refugees doubling.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;2016 was the most charitable year in American history. China’s
donations have increased more than ten times since a decade ago.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The Gates Foundation announced another 5 billion dollars towards
eradicating poverty and disease in Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Individual Canadians were so welcoming that the country set a
world standard for how to privately sponsor and resettle refugees.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Teenage birth rates in the United States have never been lower,
while at the same time graduation rates have never been higher.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;SpaceX made history by landing a rocket upright after returning
from space, potentially opening a new era of space exploration.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Finally - The Cubs won the World Series for the first time in 108
years, giving hope to Maple Leafs fans everywhere. Happy New Year.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;There are countless more examples, big and small. If you refocus on
the things that are working, your year will be better than the last.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 19:40:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.tamouse.org/quotes/2017/01/01/list-of-positive-things-in-2016.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.tamouse.org/quotes/2017/01/01/list-of-positive-things-in-2016.html</guid>
        
        <category>cmdr-hadfield</category>
        
        <category>2017</category>
        
        <category>good-stuff</category>
        
        
        <category>quotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Retrospective on 2016 for starting 2017</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So, it’s New Year’s Eve 2016. A traditional time for reflection. The
following are not resolutions, however. Taking my queue from Agile
retrospectives, I’ve written the “Do More Of, Do Less Of, and Keep the
Same”:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;things-i-want-to-do-more-of-in-2017&quot;&gt;Things I want to do more of in 2017:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;write / journal more&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;draw / sketch more&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;paint outside of painting class&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;document my learnings more often&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;organize these things and make them habitual&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;walk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;things-i-want-to-do-less-of-in-2017&quot;&gt;Things I want to do less of in 2017:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;eating carbohydrates&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;hoarding cardboard boxes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;social media&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;things-im-planning-to-keep-about-the-same-in-2017&quot;&gt;Things I’m planning to keep about the same in 2017:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;reading&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;learning&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;practicing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 20:25:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.tamouse.org/personal/2016/12/31/retrospective-on-2016-for-starting-2017.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.tamouse.org/personal/2016/12/31/retrospective-on-2016-for-starting-2017.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>no signs</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://tt.imageshare.s3.amazonaws.com/blog/poems/no-signs/webs/no-signs.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; alt=&quot;no-signs - a poem&quot; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&quot;no signs&quot;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2016 14:18:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.tamouse.org/poetry/2016/12/18/no-signs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.tamouse.org/poetry/2016/12/18/no-signs.html</guid>
        
        <category>poems</category>
        
        <category>hurt</category>
        
        
        <category>poetry</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Video: Joeseph on NPR Tiny Desk Concerts</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Joeseph is 3 sisters, Allison, Meegan, and Natalie Closner. They have
a beautiful stripped down style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;853&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/TeDh-3IKwgc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2016 08:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.tamouse.org/music/2016/11/04/video-joeseph-on-npr-tiny-desk-concerts.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.tamouse.org/music/2016/11/04/video-joeseph-on-npr-tiny-desk-concerts.html</guid>
        
        <category>youtube</category>
        
        <category>joeseph</category>
        
        <category>npr</category>
        
        <category>tiny-desk</category>
        
        
        <category>music</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Malcolm X on progress (tumblr)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As true today as it was then&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;tumblr-post&quot; data-href=&quot;https://embed.tumblr.com/embed/post/YWv_FoOPNH9Y7WuGnxJ6xQ/97262763649&quot; data-did=&quot;ad5d9ba35dd141bd8fc66402e9940f6665de52f5&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://exgynocraticgrrl-archive.tumblr.com/post/97262763649/malcolm-x-on-progress&quot;&gt;http://exgynocraticgrrl-archive.tumblr.com/post/97262763649/malcolm-x-on-progress&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.tumblr.com/post.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I will never say that progress is being made. If you stick a knife in my back 9 inches and pull it out 6 inches, there’s no progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you pull it all the way out that’s not progress.
The progress is healing the wound that the blow made.
And they haven’t even begun to pull the knife out, much
less try and heal the wound.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;They won’t even admit the knife is there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;– Malcolm X&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2016 16:52:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.tamouse.org/politics/2016/10/23/malcolm-x-on-progress-tumblr.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.tamouse.org/politics/2016/10/23/malcolm-x-on-progress-tumblr.html</guid>
        
        <category>malcolm-x</category>
        
        <category>oppression</category>
        
        <category>racism</category>
        
        <category>black-lives-matter</category>
        
        <category>blm</category>
        
        
        <category>politics</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tompkins Square Halloween Dog Parade</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Pictures from this year’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theverge.com/2016/10/22/13367414/tompkins-square-halloween-dog-parade-new-york-city-photos&quot;&gt;Tompkins Square Halloween Dog Parade&lt;/a&gt;. Seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tt.imageshare.s3.amazonaws.com/blog/critters/2016-10-23-tompkins-square-halloween-dog-parade/IMG_3882.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-thumbnail&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_3882.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tt.imageshare.s3.amazonaws.com/blog/critters/2016-10-23-tompkins-square-halloween-dog-parade/IMG_4935.JPG&quot; class=&quot;img-thumbnail&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_4935.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tt.imageshare.s3.amazonaws.com/blog/critters/2016-10-23-tompkins-square-halloween-dog-parade/IMG_4957.JPG&quot; class=&quot;img-thumbnail&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_4957.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tt.imageshare.s3.amazonaws.com/blog/critters/2016-10-23-tompkins-square-halloween-dog-parade/IMG_4969.JPG&quot; class=&quot;img-thumbnail&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_4969.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tt.imageshare.s3.amazonaws.com/blog/critters/2016-10-23-tompkins-square-halloween-dog-parade/IMG_4971.JPG&quot; class=&quot;img-thumbnail&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_4971.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tt.imageshare.s3.amazonaws.com/blog/critters/2016-10-23-tompkins-square-halloween-dog-parade/IMG_4978.JPG&quot; class=&quot;img-thumbnail&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_4978.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tt.imageshare.s3.amazonaws.com/blog/critters/2016-10-23-tompkins-square-halloween-dog-parade/IMG_4993.JPG&quot; class=&quot;img-thumbnail&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_4993.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tt.imageshare.s3.amazonaws.com/blog/critters/2016-10-23-tompkins-square-halloween-dog-parade/IMG_5004.JPG&quot; class=&quot;img-thumbnail&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_5004.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tt.imageshare.s3.amazonaws.com/blog/critters/2016-10-23-tompkins-square-halloween-dog-parade/IMG_5008.JPG&quot; class=&quot;img-thumbnail&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_5008.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tt.imageshare.s3.amazonaws.com/blog/critters/2016-10-23-tompkins-square-halloween-dog-parade/IMG_5011.JPG&quot; class=&quot;img-thumbnail&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_5011.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tt.imageshare.s3.amazonaws.com/blog/critters/2016-10-23-tompkins-square-halloween-dog-parade/IMG_5014.JPG&quot; class=&quot;img-thumbnail&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_5014.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tt.imageshare.s3.amazonaws.com/blog/critters/2016-10-23-tompkins-square-halloween-dog-parade/IMG_7653.JPG&quot; class=&quot;img-thumbnail&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_7653.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2016 16:34:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.tamouse.org/critters/2016/10/23/tompkins-square-halloween-dog-parade.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.tamouse.org/critters/2016/10/23/tompkins-square-halloween-dog-parade.html</guid>
        
        <category>dogs</category>
        
        <category>halloween</category>
        
        <category>parade</category>
        
        
        <category>critters</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
<!-- touch 1 -->
