<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&amp;#128045; the tamouse pages</title>
    <description>the rumblings and ramblings of a well-traveled tech-mouse</description>
    <link>https://blog.tamouse.org/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.tamouse.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 21:46:56 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 21:46:56 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>A picture of our times</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//s3.amazonaws.com/tt.imageshare/blog/politics/2017-06-11-a-picture-for-our-times/comey-testifying.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Photo of Director Comey testifying before Congress, June 9, 2017&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 21:36:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://blog.tamouse.org/politics/2017/06/11/a-picture-of-our-times.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.tamouse.org/politics/2017/06/11/a-picture-of-our-times.html</guid>
        
        <category>comey</category>
        
        <category>testifying</category>
        
        <category>trump</category>
        
        
        <category>politics</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Carrier Bag Theory of Fiction, by Ursula K. LeGuin</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I found this some obscure place, and wanted to house it someplace I
can find it again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-carrier-bag-theory-of-fiction&quot;&gt;The Carrier Bag Theory of Fiction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;By: Ursula K. Le Guin 1986&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Source: Dancing at the Edge of the World&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transcribed: by Cody Jones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In the temperate and tropical regions where it appears that hominids evolved into human beings, the principal food of the species was vegetable. Sixty-five to eighty percent of what human beings ate in those regions in Paleolithic, Neolithic, and prehistoric times was gathered; only in the extreme Arctic was meat the staple food. The mammoth hunters spectacularly occupy the cave wall and the mind, but what we actually did to stay alive and fat was gather seeds, roots, sprouts, shoots, leaves, nuts, berries, fruits, and grains, adding bugs and mollusks and netting or snaring birds, fish, rats, rabbits, and other tuskless small fry to up the protein. And we didn’t even work hard at it–much less hard than peasants slaving in somebody else’s field after agriculture was invented, much less hard than paid workers since civilization was invented. The average prehistoric person could make a nice living in about a fifteen-hour work week.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Fifteen hours a week for subsistence leaves a lot of time for other things. So much time that maybe the restless ones who didn’t have a baby around to enliven their life, or skill in making or cooking or singing, or very interesting thoughts to think, decided to slope off and hunt mammoths. The skillful hunters then would come staggering back with a load of meat, a lot of ivory, and a story. It wasn’t the meat that made the difference. It was the story.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;It is hard to tell a really gripping tale of how I wrested a wild-oat seed from its husk, and then another, and then another, and then another, and then another, and then I scratched my gnat bites, and Ool said something funny, and we went to the creek and got a drink and watched newts for a while, and then I found another patch of oats…. No, it does not compare, it cannot compete with how I thrust my spear deep into the titanic hairy flank while Oob, impaled on one huge sweeping tusk, writhed screaming, and blood spouted everywhere in crimson torrents, and Boob was crushed to jelly when the mammoth fell on him as I shot my unerring arrow straight through eye to brain.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;That story not only has Action, it has a Hero. Heroes are powerful. Before you know it, the men and women in the wild-oat patch and their kids and the skills of the makers and the thoughts of the thoughtful and the songs of the singers are all part of it, have all been pressed into service in the tale of the Hero. But it isn’t their story. It’s his.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;When she was planning the book that ended up as Three Guineas, Virginia Woolf wrote a heading in her notebook, “Glossary”; she had thought of reinventing English according to a new plan, in order to tell a different story. One of the entries in this glossary is heroism, defined as “botulism.” And hero, in Woolf’s dictionary, is “bottle.” The hero as bottle, a stringent reevaluation. I now propose the bottle as hero.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Not just the bottle of gin or wine, but bottle in its older sense of container in general, a thing that holds something else.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;If you haven’t got something to put it in, food will escape you–even something as uncombative and unresourceful as an oat. You put as many as you can into your stomach while they are handy, that being the primary container; but what about tomorrow morning when you wake up and it’s cold and raining and wouldn’t it be good to have just a few handfuls of oats to chew on and give little Oom to make her shut up, but how do you get more than one stomachful and one handful home? So you get up and go to the damned soggy oat patch in the rain, and wouldn’t it be a good thing if you had something to put Baby Oo Oo in so that you could pick the oats with both hands? A leaf a gourd a shell a net a bag a sling a sack a bottle a pot a box a container. A holder. A recipient.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The first cultural device was probably a recipient …. Many theorizers feel that the earliest cultural inventions must have been a container to hold gathered products and some kind of sling or net carrier.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So says Elizabeth Fisher in Women’s Creation (McGraw-Hill, 1975). But no, this cannot be. Where is that wonderful, big, long, hard thing, a bone, I believe, that the Ape Man first bashed somebody with in the movie and then, grunting with ecstasy at having achieved the first proper murder, flung up into the sky, and whirling there it became a space ship thrusting its way into the cosmos to fertilize it and produce at the end of the movie a lovely fetus, a boy of course, drifting around the Milky Way without (oddly enough) any womb, any matrix at all? I don’t know. I don’t even care. I’m not telling that story. We’ve heard it, we’ve all heard all about all the sticks spears and swords, the things to bash and poke and hit with, the long, hard things, but we have not heard about the thing to put things in, the container for the thing contained. That is a new story. That is news.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And yet old. Before–once you think about it, surely long before–the weapon, a late, luxurious, superfluous tool; long before the useful knife and ax; right along with the indispensable whacker, grinder, and digger– for what’s the use of digging up a lot of potatoes if you have nothing to lug ones you can’t eat home in–with or before the tool that forces energy outward, we made the tool that brings energy home. It makes sense to me. I am an adherent of what Fisher calls the Carrier Bag Theory of human evolution.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This theory not only explains large areas of theoretical obscurity and avoids large areas of theoretical nonsense (inhabited largely by tigers, foxes, other highly territorial mammals); it also grounds me, personally, in human culture in a way I never felt grounded before. So long as culture was explained as originating from and elaborating upon the use of long, hard objects for sticking, bashing, and killing, I never thought that I had, or wanted, any particular share in it. (“What Freud mistook for her lack of civilization is woman’s lack of loyalty to civilization,” Lillian Smith observed.) The society, the civilization they were talking about, these theoreticians, was evidently theirs; they owned it, they liked it; they were human, fully human, bashing, sticking, thrusting, killing. Wanting to be human too, I sought for evidence that I was; but if that’s what it took, to make a weapon and kill with it, then evidently I was either extremely defective as a human being, or not human at all.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;That’s right, they said. What you are is a woman. Possibly not human at all, certainly defective. Now be quiet while we go on telling the Story of the Ascent of Man the Hero.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Go on, say I, wandering off towards the wild oats, with Oo Oo in the sling and little Oom carrying the basket. You just go on telling how the mammoth fell on Boob and how Cain fell on Abel and how the bomb fell on Nagasaki and how the burning jelly fell on the villagers and how the missiles will fall on the Evil Empire, and all the other steps in the Ascent of Man.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;If it is a human thing to do to put something you want, because it’s useful, edible, or beautiful, into a bag, or a basket, or a bit of rolled bark or leaf, or a net woven of your own hair, or what have you, and then take it home with you, home being another, larger kind of pouch or bag, a container for people, and then later on you take it out and eat it or share it or store it up for winter in a solider container or put it in the medicine bundle or the shrine or the museum, the holy place, the area that contains what is sacred, and then next day you probably do much the same again–if to do that is human, if that’s what it takes, then I am a human being after all. Fully, freely, gladly, for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Not, let it be said at once, an unaggressive or uncombative human being. I am an aging, angry woman laying mightily about me with my handbag, fighting hoodlums off. However I don’t, nor does anybody else, consider myself heroic for doing so. It’s just one of those damned things you have to do in order to be able to go on gathering wild oats and telling stories.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;It is the story that makes the difference. It is the story that hid my humanity from me, the story the mammoth hunters told about bashing, thrusting, raping, killing, about the Hero. The wonderful, poisonous story of Botulism. The killer story.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;It sometimes seems that that story is approaching its end. Lest there be no more telling of stories at all, some of us out here in the wild oats, amid the alien corn, think we’d better start telling another one, which maybe people can go on with when the old one’s finished. Maybe. The trouble is, we’ve all let ourselves become part of the killer story, and so we may get finished along with it. Hence it is with a certain feeling of urgency that I seek the nature, subject, words of the other story, the untold one, the life story.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;It’s unfamiliar, it doesn’t come easily, thoughtlessly to the lips as the killer story does; but still, “untold” was an exaggeration. People have been telling the life story for ages, in all sorts of words and ways. Myths of creation and transformation, trickster stories, folktales, jokes, novels…&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The novel is a fundamentally unheroic kind of story. Of course the Hero has frequently taken it over, that being his imperial nature and uncontrollable impulse, to take everything over and run it while making stern decrees and laws to control his uncontrollable impulse to kill it. So the Hero has decreed through his mouthpieces the Lawgivers, first, that the proper shape of the narrative is that of the arrow or spear, starting here and going straight there and THOK! hitting its mark (which drops dead); second, that the central concern of narrative, including the novel, is conflict; and third, that the story isn’t any good if he isn’t in it.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;I differ with all of this. I would go so far as to say that the natural, proper, fitting shape of the novel might be that of a sack, a bag. A book holds words. Words hold things. They bear meanings. A novel is a medicine bundle, holding things in a particular, powerful relation to one another and to us.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;One relationship among elements in the novel may well be that of conflict, but the reduction of narrative to conflict is absurd. (I have read a how-to-write manual that said, “A story should be seen as a battle,” and went on about strategies, attacks, victory, etc.) Conflict, competition, stress, struggle, etc., within the narrative conceived as carrier bag/belly/box/house/medicine bundle, may be seen as necessary elements of a whole which itself cannot be characterized either as conflict or as harmony, since its purpose is neither resolution nor stasis but continuing process.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Finally, it’s clear that the Hero does not look well in this bag. He needs a stage or a pedestal or a pinnacle. You put him in a bag and he looks like a rabbit, like a potato.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;That is why I like novels: instead of heroes they have people in them.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So, when I came to write science-fiction novels, I came lugging this great heavy sack of stuff, my carrier bag full of wimps and klutzes, and tiny grains of things smaller than a mustard seed, and intricately woven nets which when laboriously unknotted are seen to contain one blue pebble, an imperturbably functioning chronometer telling the time on another world, and a mouse’s skull; full of beginnings without ends, of initiations, of losses, of transformations and translations, and far more tricks than conflicts, far fewer triumphs than snares and delusions; full of space ships that get stuck, missions that fail, and people who don’t understand. I said it was hard to make a gripping tale of how we wrested the wild oats from their husks, I didn’t say it was impossible. Who ever said writing a novel was easy?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;If science fiction is the mythology of modern technology, then its myth is tragic. “Technology,” or “modern science” (using the words as they are usually used, in an unexamined shorthand standing for the “hard” sciences and high technology founded upon continuous economic growth), is a heroic undertaking, Herculean, Promethean, conceived as triumph, hence ultimately as tragedy. The fiction embodying this myth will be, and has been, triumphant (Man conquers earth, space, aliens, death, the future, etc.) and tragic (apocalypse, holocaust, then or now).&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;If, however, one avoids the linear, progressive, Time’s-(killing)-arrow mode of the Techno-Heroic, and redefines technology and science as primarily cultural carrier bag rather than weapon of domination, one pleasant side effect is that science fiction can be seen as a far less rigid, narrow field, not necessarily Promethean or apocalyptic at all, and in fact less a mythological genre than a realistic one.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;It is a strange realism, but it is a strange reality.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Science fiction properly conceived, like all serious fiction, however funny, is a way of trying to describe what is in fact going on, what people actually do and feel, how people relate to everything else in this vast sack, this belly of the universe, this womb of things to be and tomb of things that were, this unending story. In it, as in all fiction, there is room enough to keep even Man where he belongs, in his place in the scheme of things; there is time enough to gather plenty of wild oats and sow them too, and sing to little Oom, and listen to Ool’s joke, and watch newts, and still the story isn’t over. Still there are seeds to be gathered, and room in the bag of stars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 20:07:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://blog.tamouse.org/philsophy/2017/06/03/carrier-bag-theory-by-ursula-k-leguin.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.tamouse.org/philsophy/2017/06/03/carrier-bag-theory-by-ursula-k-leguin.html</guid>
        
        <category>leguin</category>
        
        <category>carrier</category>
        
        <category>bag</category>
        
        <category>theory</category>
        
        <category>fiction</category>
        
        <category>critique</category>
        
        <category>critical-thought</category>
        
        <category>essay</category>
        
        
        <category>philsophy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>IRON Pirate Garage Buell XB9 Cafe Racer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This beauty came across my feeds a year ago, and popped back up on
facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go visit and follow the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/pg/ironpirategarage/photos/?tab=album&amp;amp;album_id=1198502130160119&quot;&gt;IRON Pirate Facebook page&lt;/a&gt; if you dare. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;figure-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://tt.imageshare.s3.amazonaws.com/blog/motorsports/Buell-XB9-Cafe-Racer-by-IRON-Pirate-Garage/buell-xb9-iron-pirate-01.jpg&quot; class=&quot;figure-img-image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;figure-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://tt.imageshare.s3.amazonaws.com/blog/motorsports/Buell-XB9-Cafe-Racer-by-IRON-Pirate-Garage/buell-xb9-iron-pirate-02.jpg&quot; class=&quot;figure-img-image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;figure-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://tt.imageshare.s3.amazonaws.com/blog/motorsports/Buell-XB9-Cafe-Racer-by-IRON-Pirate-Garage/buell-xb9-iron-pirate-03.jpg&quot; class=&quot;figure-img-image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;figure-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://tt.imageshare.s3.amazonaws.com/blog/motorsports/Buell-XB9-Cafe-Racer-by-IRON-Pirate-Garage/buell-xb9-iron-pirate-04.jpg&quot; class=&quot;figure-img-image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;figure-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://tt.imageshare.s3.amazonaws.com/blog/motorsports/Buell-XB9-Cafe-Racer-by-IRON-Pirate-Garage/buell-xb9-iron-pirate-05.jpg&quot; class=&quot;figure-img-image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 01:52:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://blog.tamouse.org/motorsports/2017/05/22/iron-pirate-garage-buell-xb9-cafe-racer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.tamouse.org/motorsports/2017/05/22/iron-pirate-garage-buell-xb9-cafe-racer.html</guid>
        
        <category>buell</category>
        
        <category>motorcycles</category>
        
        <category>cafe-racers</category>
        
        <category>machinery-as-art</category>
        
        
        <category>motorsports</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Amazing Legerro, a custom by Walt Siegl</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This was posted back in 2013, I think, or at least that’s when I
remember seeing it for the first time. I was astounded by the beauty
of this machine, I had it blown up on my computer desktop for
months. The Legerro is a series of project bikes by builder Walt
Siegl, based on the mighty Ducati.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;figure-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;//s3.amazonaws.com/tt.imageshare/blog/motorsports/2017-05-19-walt-sielg-legerro/walt-siegl-0.jpg&quot; class=&quot;figure-img-image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;figure-img&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;//s3.amazonaws.com/tt.imageshare/blog/motorsports/2017-05-19-walt-sielg-legerro/walt-siegl-5.jpg&quot; class=&quot;figure-img-image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 19:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://blog.tamouse.org/motorsports/2017/05/19/walt-siegl-legerro.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.tamouse.org/motorsports/2017/05/19/walt-siegl-legerro.html</guid>
        
        <category>motorcycles</category>
        
        <category>bikes</category>
        
        <category>caferacers</category>
        
        <category>sportsbikes</category>
        
        <category>siegl</category>
        
        <category>legerro</category>
        
        <category>amazing</category>
        
        
        <category>motorsports</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cassini image: Saturn's Rings and Enceladus Jets</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;An amazing image of Saturn’s Rings with Enceladus hovering above,
where you can see the southern polar water jets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//s3.amazonaws.com/tt.imageshare/blog/space/saturn/saturns-rings-enceladus-jets-cassini-PIA18343_hires.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 18:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://blog.tamouse.org/space/2017/05/11/cassini-image-saturns-rings-and-enceladus-jets.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.tamouse.org/space/2017/05/11/cassini-image-saturns-rings-and-enceladus-jets.html</guid>
        
        <category>space</category>
        
        <category>cassini</category>
        
        <category>saturn</category>
        
        <category>enceladus</category>
        
        <category>images</category>
        
        <category>awesome</category>
        
        
        <category>space</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Neil Makes Up Another Story</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In a recent tweet,
author &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/neilhimself&quot;&gt;Neil Gaiman&lt;/a&gt; delivers a
micro-tale. Starting from this tweet:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;
I don&amp;#39;t believe in the Tooth Fairy any more Dad so how about you
just give me my money NOW while I throw this tooth in the bin?
&lt;/p&gt;
&amp;mdash; Astrid Benn (@StuffAstridSays)
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/StuffAstridSays/status/848614419592617985&quot;&gt;April
2, 2017&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;
That night, the tooth fairy came, with her pliers &amp;amp; the
coins she took from off the eyes of the dead, to show Astrid the error
of her ways
&lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/PGRi1ZAcyY&quot;&gt;https://t.co/PGRi1ZAcyY&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&amp;mdash;
Neil Gaiman (@neilhimself)
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/neilhimself/status/848620179361857536&quot;&gt;April
2, 2017&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To which, pal John Scalzi responds:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;is&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/neilhimself&quot;&gt;@neilhimself&lt;/a&gt;
Neil.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; John Scalzi (@scalzi) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/scalzi/status/848620370223656960&quot;&gt;April 2,
2017&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neil, abashed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/scalzi&quot;&gt;@scalzi&lt;/a&gt; Sorry John.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash;
Neil Gaiman (@neilhimself) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/neilhimself/status/848620751146143744&quot;&gt;April
2, 2017&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/face-with-tears-of-joy.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 16:12:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://blog.tamouse.org/quotes/2017/04/02/neil-makes-up-another-story.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.tamouse.org/quotes/2017/04/02/neil-makes-up-another-story.html</guid>
        
        <category>neil-gaiman</category>
        
        <category>twitter</category>
        
        
        <category>quotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Emma Watson Quote: Feminism is not a stick to beat other women with</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Giving an interview to Reuters during pressers for the new live-action
film “Beauty and the Beast”, actor Emma Watson summed up the essense
of what is wrong with white, non-intersectional feminism:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“It just always reveals to me how many misconceptions and what a misunderstanding there is about what feminism is,” she said during an interview with Reuters. “Feminism is about giving women choice, feminism is not a stick with which to beat other women with, it’s about freedom, it’s about liberation, it’s about equality. I really don’t know what my tits have to do with it. It’s very confusing.”
– Emma Watson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 22:44:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://blog.tamouse.org/feminism/2017/03/05/emma-watson-quote-feminism-is-not-a-stick-to-beat-other-women-with.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.tamouse.org/feminism/2017/03/05/emma-watson-quote-feminism-is-not-a-stick-to-beat-other-women-with.html</guid>
        
        <category>emma-watson</category>
        
        <category>feminism</category>
        
        <category>quote</category>
        
        
        <category>feminism</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>It is not normal... (tumblr)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Over on tumblr…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;tumblr-post&quot; data-href=&quot;https://embed.tumblr.com/embed/post/qqNvGYhq3c_RzjpEWaoRdw/123007553626&quot; data-did=&quot;1024447b735ddde2fb37e02ec89b5639b8390d72&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://transcendentalbrilliance.tumblr.com/post/123007553626/its-not-normal-for-your-boyfriend-to-ignore-you&quot;&gt;http://transcendentalbrilliance.tumblr.com/post/123007553626/its-not-normal-for-your-boyfriend-to-ignore-you&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://assets.tumblr.com/post.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in plain text:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it’s not normal for your boyfriend to ignore you when you want to talk to him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it’s not normal for your boyfriend to shove you when he’s angry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it’s not normal for your boyfriend to call you a dumbass or a bitch when you’re in an argument.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it’s not normal for your boyfriend to threaten to leave the relationship every time you defend yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it’s not normal for your boyfriend to invalidate your feelings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it’s not normal for your boyfriend to not tell you who he’s with or where he’s going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it’s not normal for your boyfriend to keep making the same detrimental mistake over and over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it’s not normal for your boyfriend to use your insecurities against you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it’s not normal for your boyfriend to make you feel guilty for having desires and needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it’s not normal for your boyfriend to tell you that you’re stupid when you cry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it’s not normal for your boyfriend to cheat on you because he’s “just a stupid guy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it’s not normal for your boyfriend to rely on you when he doesn’t do a thing for himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it’s not normal for your boyfriend to hurt you intentionally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;please stop normalizing toxic romantic relationships. it’s not healthy
for your partner to upset you and behave recklessly as long as he
apologizes later. apologies mean nothing after he has repeatedly
disrespected you. kisses and hugs mean nothing after he has repeatedly
disrespected you. public displays of affection mean nothing after he
has repeatedly disrespected you. promises mean nothing after he has
repeatedly disrespected you. it is not okay for him to hurt you
physically or emotionally because he said he’ll change. he hasn’t. he
won’t. get out now because THIS! IS! NOT! NORMAL! other couples do not
go through this. other couples did NOT have to go through this to be
in a happy, wholesome place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;he is manipulative and selfish and he is making you weak every time
you agree to stay. even when you feel like “maybe this time, things
will be okay,” they won’t – that’s what he wants you to think so you
never slip from his grasp. you know as well as i do you’re 50 times
overdue for “this is his last chance.” this is not normal.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 20:47:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://blog.tamouse.org/oppression/2017/03/05/it-is-not-normal-dot-dot-dot-tumblr.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.tamouse.org/oppression/2017/03/05/it-is-not-normal-dot-dot-dot-tumblr.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>oppression</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Anxiety Behaviours</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Anxiety can be very harmful and it’s not something to be overlooked.
The worst problem is that a lot of people can’t understand the effects
it can have on a person and find anxious people as being lazy,
irresponsible and passive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are not an anxious person, knowing this can help you understand
anxiety a bit better. If you are, we are sure you are going to agree
with these things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;decline-invites-although-you-may-want-to-go&quot;&gt;Decline invites although you may want to go&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are certain days that you may have planned all along and when
they come, anxiety takes up the whole space. It can become so
debilitating that you feel as if you lack the energy to go out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are aware of what is happening to you and you don’t want to become
a burden where you are supposed to go - so you just cancel everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;obsess-over-trivial-things-other-people-may-not-even-notice&quot;&gt;Obsess over trivial things other people may not even notice&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A simple word or an unintended glance from someone is enough for your
head to start processing and rewinding the situation even for days! The
truth is you obsess over everything that has happened recently or a
week ago, or any time ago, really.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may obsess over a conversation you had, or the fact that someone
hasn’t texted you yet (after a whole 12 hour period) or really just
over the fact that some stranger looked at you as if they knew you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever the case may be, many would get confused by the notion that
you even notice such things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;go-to-bed-late-wake-up-early-in-the-morning&quot;&gt;Go to bed late, wake up early in the morning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest issues for you is certainly sleeping. Of all the
processing in your head after the day, you find it hard to go to bed on
time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When early morning comes, your anxiety clock starts ticking again and
ringing several alarms to get things going - even though you are tired.
When your anxiety has switched on (by waking up), you can’t do anything
to switch it off, so you don’t go back to bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;in-every-situation-the-worst-scenario-is-your-biggest-thought&quot;&gt;In every situation, the worst scenario is your biggest thought&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of enjoying the moment as it is, you can’t help picturing and
convincing yourself that the worst scenario is inevitable. If it’s a
first date, you are convinced that something will go terribly wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you get sick, you always manage to connect the symptoms to the worst
diseases you can imagine. It’s as if your mind tricks you into
believing that nothing can go right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;you-rewind-conversations-in-your-head---over-and-over-again&quot;&gt;You rewind conversations in your head - over and over again&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter how well a conversation went with somebody, you always replay
that conversation in your head fearing that you may have said something
wrong. That’s why you try to avoid confrontation at all cost.
[INS: :INS]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This constant rewinding seems to be able to haunt you until it starts
chipping a hole from the inside. You always have to remind yourself
that it’s your anxiety talking and that there is most certainly nothing
wrong with what you have said in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;when-someone-shows-concern-about-you-you-become-even-more-worried-about-the-same-thing&quot;&gt;When someone shows concern about you, you become even more worried about the same thing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If someone notices that you are not OK and shows concern, your anxiety
grows even more. The thing is, when you hear someone asking if you are
alright, it makes you fear even more for yourself and your state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You think - if it has become noticeable, then there has to be more to
it than I thought. This makes you feel worse than you did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;you-believe-that-you-are-to-blame-if-someone-doesnt-reply-right-away&quot;&gt;You believe that you are to blame if someone doesn’t reply right away&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When communicating with people, be it your significant other, a friend
or a relative, if they don’t respond immediately, you start thinking
that you may have said or done something wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, you should stop and consider that they may be in the middle of
something that takes up their attention, or that they are just bad at
communicating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;you-are-experiencing-a-breakdown-when-the-future-comes-as-a-topic&quot;&gt;You are experiencing a breakdown when the future comes as a topic&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While most people look forward to the future and make plans for the
future, your view on the future is making you feel intimidated and
frustrated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Experiencing the present so hard makes you think how hard and daunting
the future may be. This makes you retreat and hide from the thought of
it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;you-always-compare-your-success-to-others-who-are-your-age&quot;&gt;You always compare your success to others who are your age&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although you may not want to compare yourself to others, your anxiety
makes you scour through Facebook and stay up to date with all the
successful things your peers have done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your worries are not that they have managed to succeed, but if you are
ever going to succeed in your life like they have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;you-replay-every-mistake-you-make-and-beat-yourself-up-over-it&quot;&gt;You replay every mistake you make and beat yourself up over it&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The worst scenario is making a mistake at work. The thoughts that will
consume you afterwards are tremendously difficult to handle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although you strive to perfect whatever you are doing, mistakes can
occur, which is natural. Unfortunately, your anxiety doesn’t know that.
In such cases, it becomes your worst enemy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-some-days-you-are-too-physically-and-mentally-exhausted-to-even-get-out-of-bed&quot;&gt;On some days, you are too physically and mentally exhausted to even get out of bed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anxiety burns up most of your energy, both mentally and physically.
That’s why it can happen that you cannot function properly and you just
want to remain in bed and leave yourself drown in the sheets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This paralysis comes as a result of the overwhelming experiences due
to your anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 13:13:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://blog.tamouse.org/psychology/2017/02/20/anxiety-behaviours.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.tamouse.org/psychology/2017/02/20/anxiety-behaviours.html</guid>
        
        <category>anxiety</category>
        
        
        <category>psychology</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>tweet: largest protest in US history</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The data is in: 2017 Womens March largest protest in USA history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Via UConn prof &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/djpressman&quot;&gt;@djpressman&lt;/a&gt;, between 3.3 million to 4.2 million people marched today. Largest protests in US history &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/DA6gR2QFs6&quot;&gt;https://t.co/DA6gR2QFs6&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/O3PZ6O6Dim&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/O3PZ6O6Dim&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Ari Berman (@AriBerman) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AriBerman/status/823001984085164032&quot;&gt;January 22, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 22:54:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://blog.tamouse.org/politics/2017/01/21/tweet-largest-protest-in-us-history.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.tamouse.org/politics/2017/01/21/tweet-largest-protest-in-us-history.html</guid>
        
        <category>womensmarch</category>
        
        
        <category>politics</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
<!-- touch 1 -->
